<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Matt Truwit | Emanuele Bardelli</title><link>/authors/matt-truwit/</link><atom:link href="/authors/matt-truwit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Matt Truwit</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2016-2023 Emanuele Bardelli</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>/media/icon_huab161a8a6141c44005e6f1e87022f28c_150734_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Matt Truwit</title><link>/authors/matt-truwit/</link></image><item><title>Cultivating coaching in clinical mentors: An experimental evaluation of the Mentors Matter professional development</title><link>/publication/ronfeldt-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/ronfeldt-2022/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Room for Improvement? Mentor Teachers and the Evolution of Teacher Preservice Clinical Evaluations</title><link>/publication/goldhaber-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/goldhaber-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>The clinical teaching experience is one of the most important components of teacher preparation. Prior observational research has found that more effective mentors and schools with better professional climates are associated with better preparation for teacher candidates. We test these findings using an experimental assignment of teacher candidates to placement sites in two states. Candidates who were randomly assigned to higher quality placement sites experienced larger improvements in performance over the course of the clinical experience, as evaluated by field instructors (a.k.a university instructors). The findings suggest that improving clinical placement procedures can improve the teaching quality of candidates.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Improving preservice teachers’ feelings of preparedness to teach through recruitment of instructionally effective and experienced cooperating teachers: A randomized experiment</title><link>/publication/ronfeldt-2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/ronfeldt-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p>New studies show that the instructional effectiveness of preservice candidates and their cooperating teachers are positively related. However, we neither know if these relationships are causal nor, assuming they are, if it is possible to significantly increase the instructional effectiveness of the cooperating teacher pool. In this study, we randomly assign districts to receive recommendation lists (generated using administrative data) for the recruitment of more promising cooperating teachers. Districts receiving lists recruited significantly more effective/experienced cooperating teachers, while candidates placed in these districts felt significantly better prepared to teach. As a result, this study offers an innovative, low-cost strategy for recruiting effective/experienced cooperating teachers and presents the first causal estimates that more effective/experienced cooperating teachers improve candidates’ preparedness to teach.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Learning from the best: Promising practices in preparing Tennessee’s future teachers</title><link>/publication/morris-2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/morris-2020/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Room for Improvement? Mentor Teachers and the Evolution of Teacher Preservice Clinical Evaluations</title><link>/publication/goldhaber-2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/goldhaber-2020/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Improving student teachers’ feelings of preparedness to teach through recruitment of instructionally effective and experienced cooperating teachers: A randomized experiment</title><link>/publication/ronfeldt-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/ronfeldt-2019/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>