<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2 | Emanuele Bardelli</title><link>/publication-type/2/</link><atom:link href="/publication-type/2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>2</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2016-2023 Emanuele Bardelli</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>/media/icon_huab161a8a6141c44005e6f1e87022f28c_150734_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>2</title><link>/publication-type/2/</link></image><item><title>Development of the Short Critical Consciousness Scale (ShoCCS)</title><link>/publication/diemer-2020/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/diemer-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p>Critical consciousness represents the analysis and critique of structural inequalities, the motivation and perceived capacity to effect change, and social action to redress inequity. A wave of recent instruments measuring critical consciousness has been rigorously validated. Yet, whether these measures efficiently assess different levels of critical consciousness or contain redundant, or non-informative, items remain unknown. This research develops a short version (Short CCS, or ShoCCS) of the previously validated Critical Consciousness Scale. Using Item Response Theory methods, the long-form CCS is scrutinized for redundant items to efficiently measure critical reflection, critical motivation, and critical action. The resulting 13-item ShoCCS yields an internally consistent instrument with similar information distributions as the longer measure. Since the ShoCCS places less financial and time burden on investigators and respondents in comparison to the original CCS, and includes a new measure of critical motivation, it may streamline CC measurement in scholarship, practice, and policy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How can teaching simulations help us study at scale the tensions mathematics teachers have to manage when considering policy recommendations?</title><link>/publication/herbst-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/herbst-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>The investigation at scale of the tensions that teachers need to manage when deciding to follow recommendations for practice has been hampered by the problem of occurrence: The conditions in which those decisions could be made need to occur during an observation in order for observers to document how teachers handle them. Simulations have been recommended as a way to immerse teachers in instructional contexts in which they have the opportunity to follow such recommendations and observe what teachers choose to do in response. In this article, we show an example of how a teaching simulation may be used to support such investigation, in the context of policy recommendations to open up classroom discussion and consider multiple solutions and in the instructional situation of doing proofs in geometry. A contrast between the decisions made by expert and novice teachers (n=59) in the simulation, analyzed using multiple regression, adds empirical evidence to earlier conjectures based on qualitative analysis of classroom teaching experiments that revealed teachers to be particularly attentive to epistemological and temporal constraints. We found that expert and novice teachers differed in how likely they were to prefer practices recommended by policymakers. Specifically, expert teachers were significantly more likely than novice teachers to open up classroom discussions when they had the knowledge resources to correct a student error. Similarly, expert teachers were significantly more likely than novice teachers to explore multiple solutions when there were no time constraints.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Room for Improvement? Mentor Teachers and the Evolution of Teacher Preservice Clinical Evaluations</title><link>/publication/goldhaber-2022/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/goldhaber-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>The clinical teaching experience is one of the most important components of teacher preparation. Prior observational research has found that more effective mentors and schools with better professional climates are associated with better preparation for teacher candidates. We test these findings using an experimental assignment of teacher candidates to placement sites in two states. Candidates who were randomly assigned to higher quality placement sites experienced larger improvements in performance over the course of the clinical experience, as evaluated by field instructors (a.k.a university instructors). The findings suggest that improving clinical placement procedures can improve the teaching quality of candidates.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Workforce outcomes of program completers in high needs areas</title><link>/publication/bardelli-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/bardelli-2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>Purpose: For decades, federal and state agencies have identified teacher shortages in high-needs endorsement areas (HNEAs), including science, mathematics, and special education, as a critical problem. Many states have implemented policies and practices to recruit HNEA teachers, but little is known about how their workforce outcomes compare with other teachers. Research Methods: We leverage statewide longitudinal data in Tennessee to analyze the workforce outcomes of teachers prepared in the state between 2010 and 2016. We model our outcomes of interest using linear and logistic multilevel regression. Findings: We observe that the number of teachers who receive HNEA endorsements has increased over time even as the overall number of teachers prepared in the state has declined. HNEA teachers are employed at higher rates and retained at similar rates as other teachers. HNEA teachers have similar student achievement gains as non-HNEA teachers. Though HNEA and non-HNEA teachers also have similar first-year observation ratings, STEM (science, technology, engineering, and mathematics) and special education teachers improve at slower rates subsequently. Implications: Our results suggest that potential policy solutions to the recruitment, retention, and development of highly effective HNEA teachers might require policies targeted to individual HNEAs, as each area might have unique needs and challenges. The positive results on preparation and employment of HNEA teachers suggest that Tennessee’s policies to train, employ, and retain HNEA teachers have been largely successful. However, our findings also suggest that HNEA teachers may need additional supports in instructional development.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Improving preservice teachers’ feelings of preparedness to teach through recruitment of instructionally effective and experienced cooperating teachers: A randomized experiment</title><link>/publication/ronfeldt-2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/ronfeldt-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p>New studies show that the instructional effectiveness of preservice candidates and their cooperating teachers are positively related. However, we neither know if these relationships are causal nor, assuming they are, if it is possible to significantly increase the instructional effectiveness of the cooperating teacher pool. In this study, we randomly assign districts to receive recommendation lists (generated using administrative data) for the recruitment of more promising cooperating teachers. Districts receiving lists recruited significantly more effective/experienced cooperating teachers, while candidates placed in these districts felt significantly better prepared to teach. As a result, this study offers an innovative, low-cost strategy for recruiting effective/experienced cooperating teachers and presents the first causal estimates that more effective/experienced cooperating teachers improve candidates’ preparedness to teach.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Will mentoring a student teacher harm my evaluation scores? Effects of serving as a cooperating teacher on evaluation metrics</title><link>/publication/ronfeldt-2020-a/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/ronfeldt-2020-a/</guid><description>&lt;p>Growing evidence suggests that preservice candidates receive better coaching and are more instructionally effective when they are mentored by more instructionally effective cooperating teachers (CTs). Yet teacher education program leaders indicate it can be difficult to recruit instructionally effective teachers to serve as CTs, in part because teachers worry that serving may negatively impact district evaluation scores. Using a unique data set on over 4,500 CTs, we compare evaluation scores during years these teachers served as CTs with years they did not. In years they served as CTs, teachers had significantly better observation ratings and somewhat better achievement gains, though not always at significant levels. These results suggest that concerns over lowered evaluations should not prevent teachers from serving as CTs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The role of simulations for supporting professional growth: Teachers’ engagement in virtual professional experimentation</title><link>/publication/milewski-2018/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/milewski-2018/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>