<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hannah Mullman | Emanuele Bardelli</title><link>/authors/hannah-mullman/</link><atom:link href="/authors/hannah-mullman/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Hannah Mullman</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2016-2022 Emanuele Bardelli</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 08:15:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><image><url>/media/icon_hu7ab6927c01d24bf409ed7328930b5c92_1836911_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Hannah Mullman</title><link>/authors/hannah-mullman/</link></image><item><title>Effects of using administrative data to guide the recruitment of instructionally effective and experienced cooperating teachers: Results from a randomized control trial</title><link>/talk/recruitment-rct/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 08:15:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>/talk/recruitment-rct/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.aera.net/Newsroom/AERA-Announces-2020-Annual-Meeting-Change" target="_blank" rel="noopener">This talk has been cancelled&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to receive initial teacher certification, teacher candidates complete
clinical training, often referred to as “student teaching” or “residency,” in
the classroom of a cooperating teacher (CT) – a P-12 teacher who mentors them
as they take on classroom teaching responsibilities. There is increasing
evidence that clinical training generally, and CTs specifically, have
important influences on preservice student teacher (PST) development. New
research shows that teacher candidates who were mentored by instructionally
effective teachers are more instructionally effective themselves once
employed, suggesting that teacher education programs and district/school
leaders should recruit more instructionally effective teachers to serve as CTs
(Authors, 2018a; Authors 2018b; Goldhaber et al., 2018). However, program
leaders report that it is often difficult to recruit instructionally effective
teachers to serve as mentors for a variety of reasons, including: (1) school
and district leaders may be resistant to hand responsibility of instruction to
novice teachers in the classrooms of their strongest teachers, (2) school,
district and program leaders may not know who their most instructionally
effective teachers are, and (3) these different stakeholders may have
competing criteria for selecting mentors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this initiative, we used prior information on instructional performance and
years of experience (from administrative data) to identify the most
instructionally effective and experienced potential CTs in the specific
districts, subjects and grade levels needed by a large program that partnered
with us. Our state partners, with our technical support, then randomly
assigned neighboring districts to receive these targeted recruitment lists (or
not) and requested district leaders who received the lists to begin their
recruitment with teachers named on the lists; district leaders were also
advised to use their best judgement where they felt it inappropriate or unwise
for any listed teachers to serve. We investigate whether receiving these lists
(1) increases the instructional quality of the CTs that are actually recruited
and (2) improves feelings of preparedness, based upon data collected from
online surveys completed by PSTs at the end of their clinical training.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We find that CTs in treatment districts have, on average, substantially higher
evaluation scores than CTs in control districts. These differences are
significant on observation ratings (0.332 s.d. units), TVAAS scores (0.654
s.d. units), and years of experience (0.558 s.d. units). Furthermore, at the
end of clinical training, PSTs in treatment districts reported feeling
significantly better prepared on both questioning practices (0.660 standard
deviation units) and other instructional skills (0.576 standard deviation
units). On the other hand, PSTs in treatment and control districts reported
statistically similar rates of mentoring and coaching activities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These results suggest that the recruitment of CTs is a feasible and effective
lever to improve teacher education. As our intervention uses evaluation and
personnel data that is readily available at the district and state level,
using prior information to aid the recruitment of CTs is a low-cost
intervention that can significantly impact the overall instructional quality
of CTs, as well as their PSTs’ readiness to teach.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Improving preservice teachers’ feelings of preparedness to teach through recruitment of instructionally effective and experienced cooperating teachers: A randomized experiment</title><link>/publication/ronfeldt-2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/ronfeldt-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p>New studies show that the instructional effectiveness of preservice candidates and their cooperating teachers are positively related. However, we neither know if these relationships are causal nor, assuming they are, if it is possible to significantly increase the instructional effectiveness of the cooperating teacher pool. In this study, we randomly assign districts to receive recommendation lists (generated using administrative data) for the recruitment of more promising cooperating teachers. Districts receiving lists recruited significantly more effective/experienced cooperating teachers, while candidates placed in these districts felt significantly better prepared to teach. As a result, this study offers an innovative, low-cost strategy for recruiting effective/experienced cooperating teachers and presents the first causal estimates that more effective/experienced cooperating teachers improve candidates’ preparedness to teach.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Room for Improvement? Mentor Teachers and the Evolution of Teacher Preservice Clinical Evaluations</title><link>/publication/goldhaber-2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/goldhaber-2020/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Will mentoring a student teacher harm my evaluation scores? Effects of serving as a cooperating teacher on evaluation metrics</title><link>/publication/ronfeldt-2020-a/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/ronfeldt-2020-a/</guid><description>&lt;p>Growing evidence suggests that preservice candidates receive better coaching and are more instructionally effective when they are mentored by more instructionally effective cooperating teachers (CTs). Yet teacher education program leaders indicate it can be difficult to recruit instructionally effective teachers to serve as CTs, in part because teachers worry that serving may negatively impact district evaluation scores. Using a unique data set on over 4,500 CTs, we compare evaluation scores during years these teachers served as CTs with years they did not. In years they served as CTs, teachers had significantly better observation ratings and somewhat better achievement gains, though not always at significant levels. These results suggest that concerns over lowered evaluations should not prevent teachers from serving as CTs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Improving student teachers’ feelings of preparedness to teach through recruitment of instructionally effective and experienced cooperating teachers: A randomized experiment</title><link>/publication/ronfeldt-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/ronfeldt-2019/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Can administrative data help identify promising clinical placements? Evidence from a randomized control trial in a teacher preparation program</title><link>/talk/placements-rcts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 09:45:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/talk/placements-rcts/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>