<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Matthew Truwit | Emanuele Bardelli</title><link>/authors/matthew-truwit/</link><atom:link href="/authors/matthew-truwit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Matthew Truwit</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2016-2021 Emanuele Bardelli</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><image><url>/media/icon_hubac3c42843edbede6c472e3a447f5365_155452_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Matthew Truwit</title><link>/authors/matthew-truwit/</link></image><item><title>Teacher Evaluation Systems: Measures of Instructional Effectiveness or Mechanisms of Structural Bias?</title><link>/talk/anti-racist-colloquium-may/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/talk/anti-racist-colloquium-may/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Replicating and Extending the Mentors Matter Recruitment Initiative Findings</title><link>/talk/mentoring-panel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/talk/mentoring-panel/</guid><description>&lt;p>Emerging research in teacher education is showing that cooperating teachers (CTs) have a substantial impact on preservice student teachers’ (PSTs’) future teaching trajectories. In large-scale observational studies of recent graduates in Tennessee and Washington state (Goldhaber, Krieg, &amp;amp; Theobald, 2020; Ronfeldt, Brockman, &amp;amp; Campbell, 2018), researchers found that PSTs who were placed with more instructionally effective CTs were more instructionally effective themselves.The correlational nature of these studies, though, raised questions about whether these relationships were truly causal or just spurious correlations due to outside factors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Addressing concerns over causality, recent randomized control trials have found positive effects of being placed with a more instructionally effective mentor on self-reported survey outcomes collected at the end of the student teaching experience. Ronfeldt, Goldhaber, Cowan, et al. (2018) found that student teachers assigned to more instructionally effective mentors reported receiving significantly more frequent and better coaching, as well as more opportunities to practice various instructional strategies. However, they found nonsignificant, though trending positive, differences between the treatment and control groups on feelings of preparedness to teach.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By contrast, the Mentors Matter Recruitment (MMR) initiative - the focus of this proposal - found positive effects on PSTs feelings of preparedness to teach (Ronfeldt, Bardelli, Mullman, et al., 2019). Partnering with one large program, Ronfeldt and colleagues used prior teacher evaluation information to identify the most instructionally effective teachers and sent recommendation lists to randomly selected partner districts to target their CT recruitment. Districts that received these lists recruited substantially more effective CTs and their candidate felt significantly better prepared. This paper discusses the replication efforts for the MMR initiative.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first replication study fully replicates the results for the MMR initiative. Districts that were randomized to receive the recruitment lists were able to recruit significantly and meaningfully more instructionally effective and experienced CTs. As before, PSTs assigned to these CTs reported feeling better prepared at the end of their clinical experiences. Finally, PSTs still reported no significant differences in the kind of, frequency of, and satisfaction with the coaching they experienced.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The second replication study finds that the recruitment lists can be implemented on a large scale beyond the initial teacher preparation program that participated in the first RCTs. Participating teacher education programs were able to use the recruitment lists without major modifications to recruit the needed mentor cohort. Analysis of the effects on mentor quality and student teacher outcomes is underway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two major findings emerge from these replications studies. First, we were able to replicate the positive findings on mentor quality and student teacher feelings of preparation when implementing the MMR initiative a second time. This provides confirmatory evidence that the MMR initiative’s positive results were not a one-off result but rather a robust finding that can inform teacher education policy and practice. Second, the re-implementation with multiple teacher education programs provide initial evidence that this intervention can work at scale to inform the selection and recruitment of effective teachers to serve as clinical mentors.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Improving Preservice Teachers’ Feelings of Preparedness to Teach through Recruitment of Instructionally Effective and Experienced Cooperating Teachers: A Randomized Experiment</title><link>/publication/ronfeldt-2020-a/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/ronfeldt-2020-a/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Effects of using administrative data to guide the recruitment of instructionally effective and experienced cooperating teachers: Results from a randomized control trial</title><link>/talk/recruitment-rct/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 08:15:00 -0800</pubDate><guid>/talk/recruitment-rct/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.aera.net/Newsroom/AERA-Announces-2020-Annual-Meeting-Change" target="_blank" rel="noopener">This talk has been cancelled&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to receive initial teacher certification, teacher candidates complete
clinical training, often referred to as “student teaching” or “residency,” in
the classroom of a cooperating teacher (CT) – a P-12 teacher who mentors them
as they take on classroom teaching responsibilities. There is increasing
evidence that clinical training generally, and CTs specifically, have
important influences on preservice student teacher (PST) development. New
research shows that teacher candidates who were mentored by instructionally
effective teachers are more instructionally effective themselves once
employed, suggesting that teacher education programs and district/school
leaders should recruit more instructionally effective teachers to serve as CTs
(Authors, 2018a; Authors 2018b; Goldhaber et al., 2018). However, program
leaders report that it is often difficult to recruit instructionally effective
teachers to serve as mentors for a variety of reasons, including: (1) school
and district leaders may be resistant to hand responsibility of instruction to
novice teachers in the classrooms of their strongest teachers, (2) school,
district and program leaders may not know who their most instructionally
effective teachers are, and (3) these different stakeholders may have
competing criteria for selecting mentors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this initiative, we used prior information on instructional performance and
years of experience (from administrative data) to identify the most
instructionally effective and experienced potential CTs in the specific
districts, subjects and grade levels needed by a large program that partnered
with us. Our state partners, with our technical support, then randomly
assigned neighboring districts to receive these targeted recruitment lists (or
not) and requested district leaders who received the lists to begin their
recruitment with teachers named on the lists; district leaders were also
advised to use their best judgement where they felt it inappropriate or unwise
for any listed teachers to serve. We investigate whether receiving these lists
(1) increases the instructional quality of the CTs that are actually recruited
and (2) improves feelings of preparedness, based upon data collected from
online surveys completed by PSTs at the end of their clinical training.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We find that CTs in treatment districts have, on average, substantially higher
evaluation scores than CTs in control districts. These differences are
significant on observation ratings (0.332 s.d. units), TVAAS scores (0.654
s.d. units), and years of experience (0.558 s.d. units). Furthermore, at the
end of clinical training, PSTs in treatment districts reported feeling
significantly better prepared on both questioning practices (0.660 standard
deviation units) and other instructional skills (0.576 standard deviation
units). On the other hand, PSTs in treatment and control districts reported
statistically similar rates of mentoring and coaching activities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These results suggest that the recruitment of CTs is a feasible and effective
lever to improve teacher education. As our intervention uses evaluation and
personnel data that is readily available at the district and state level,
using prior information to aid the recruitment of CTs is a low-cost
intervention that can significantly impact the overall instructional quality
of CTs, as well as their PSTs’ readiness to teach.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Learning from the Best: Promising Practices in Preparing Tennessee's Future Teachers</title><link>/publication/morris-2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/morris-2020/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Improving Student Teachers’ Feelings of Preparedness to Teach through Recruitment of Instructionally Effective and Experienced Cooperating Teachers: A Randomized Experiment</title><link>/publication/ronfeldt-2019-a/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publication/ronfeldt-2019-a/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Can administrative data help identify promising clinical placements? Evidence from a randomized control trial in a teacher preparation program</title><link>/talk/placements-rcts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 09:45:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/talk/placements-rcts/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>